- "Previously on The Mentalist..."
- Grace and I
we always thought that you
and Lisbon would get together.
"This is
Special Agent Marcus Pike."
"He's being attached to our team
while we work the case."
I like you and I think you're
a hell of a good-looking woman
and I'd love
to get to know you better.
If the offer still stands
the answer is yes.
Let's get married.
Yes.
Wait!
What are you doing here?
There's something
I need to say.
The truth is I love you.
Did you mean what you said?
- Yes, I did.
- Good.
Hello?
I know you.
- Morning.
Hey.
- Your coffee.
- Thank you.
It's a beautiful day.
You wanna sit out here?
Yeah, you can just push
all that stuff to the side.
It's going in the garage.
I'll take it around there
in a minute.
- It's a lovely day.
- Yeah.
Should think about getting you
a key to this place, huh?
Well, that's a step.
- Yeah.
- Uh, it would make things easier.
Okay.
What do we have in here? Hm?
Vintage car? Well, that should definitely
be garaged.
You don't really strike me
as a vintage-car kinda girl.
It was a graduation gift
from my grandfather.
I think it was his favorite.
Thank you for helping
move all this.
It's my pleasure.
It's been nice.
We're gonna have to get back into
the real world at some point, though.
- Yeah. Really?
- Really.
Do you wanna talk about
how we're gonna do that, maybe, or...
Sure.
Okay.
Sorry.
Abbott.
- What's up, boss?
- "Lisbon!"
"I know you still have time left
on your leave"
"but I need your help.
Do you mind suiting up?"
Not at all.
What's the case?
It's a homicide.
It's complicated.
- I'll text you the address.
- "Okay."
You know where I can find Jane?
I have no idea where he is.
All right.
I'll track him down.
- Okay.
- "See you there."
Bye.
You really have no idea
where I am?
It just seemed like
the thing to say.
- You embarrassed?
- No! God, no.
It's okay
if you're embarrassed.
No, it's just... things with Marcus
just sort of went down
and I just would like
to keep my private life private.
Just for the moment.
Not forever or anything, and...
- Is that okay?
- Yeah, sure. That's fine.
- Don't worry. Yeah.
- You're sure?
- Okay.
- I understand.
Okay.
- My turn.
- Okay.
Hi, Abbott.
Hey, Cho.
How you doing?
- Good. You?
- I'm good.
- Not going to Washington?
- No.
- Not marrying Pike?
Okay.
Victim's name
is Jeremy Geist. Shot twice.
Some customers from the bowling alley
found him a little after 2 A.M.
Apparently, he was a regular.
Looks like
a run-of-the-mill homicide.
Can't Austin P.D. handle it?
What are we doing here?
You got me.
Abbott just said "get here".
Hey, Cho.
Gimme some sugar, baby.
There we are.
- Looking good.
- Thanks.
- Hey, Lisbon.
- Jane.
Look good, too.
Got some pecan nuts.
You want some?
Um, no.
I could...
- You?
- No, thanks.
Okay. More for me.
- Boss.
- Hey.
Hey, Abbott.
Well, we have to be careful
with this one.
Austin P.D. doesn't know it,
but...
the victim, Geist,
was FBI working undercover.
And we are not releasing that.
So, gather whatever information
you can.
Get back to the office.
We're being briefed in an hour.
Cho, let's go talk
to the lead officer in charge.
Yep.
- That went okay, huh?
- Yeah, I thought it went very well.
I'm gonna head back to the office.
Uh, see you later.
- What is that in your pocket?
- What?
All right. Can I have
everyone's attention please.
This is Ken Spackman.
He's running the joint
FBI and ATF task force
that sent
Jeremy Geist undercover.
I just notified his family
in Pittsburgh.
This is uh...
This is such a blow.
Jeremy was
a first-rate agent. So...
Big blow for them, I'm sure.
Not so much for you, though.
- You barely knew Geist.
- That's correct.
Um, he came to us
from the Savannah office
a few months back.
We needed somebody who wouldn't
be recognized in Austin.
Uh, what was the assignment?
There's a gang that's been stealing
military-issue firearms
from army bases and selling them
to drug dealers.
So, we got a report
that the Rocket Bowl parking lot
is where the guns were
changing hands.
We figured somebody there was
involved, likely as a salesman.
We sent Geist in undercover
in hopes that he could tell us who it was.
Any luck?
Not yet,
but he was getting close.
We're gonna send another agent in
in a couple weeks.
In the meantime, you can't
disclose that Geist was FBI.
- It'll blow the whole thing.
- That's not gonna be easy.
There's a good chance
Geist was killed
because somebody
blew his cover.
We need to be able
to ask questions about that.
You have to understand
what's at stake, okay?
Now, we get the salesman,
we can flip him
which means
we can get the whole gang.
But if it gets out that we had
an undercover agent in place
then the operation will shut down
and the whole gang will scatter.
Well, that's not so bad.
And from the way he's acting
uh, there's a chance that
Spackman here is the killer.
He's practically in our laps.
- I'm sorry. What did you say?
- Or not. Could go either way.
Point being, it's all fine.
- I...
- I'm sorry, who...?
I think we all understand
how to do the job here.
So let's get ready
to roll out in 15 minutes.
Let's.
Hey.
- Hi. Welcome back. We missed you.
- Thanks.
Uh, where's Fischer?
Is she out sick?
- No, she transferred.
- Really? Where?
Seattle. Her mother's there.
She had a stroke,
so she went to take care of her.
Ooh. She asked me
to give you this.
Abbott says they're assigning us
a rookie
from Quantico
to fill out the team.
That should be interesting.
Oh, that's sweet.
Thank you.
You're FBI, right?
Who's Cho?
- I am.
- Hey, Mason Hunston.
I'm the owner.
Anything we can do to help.
I mean, we've had some fights
from time to time
but nothing like this.
Were you here
when it happened?
Uh, I was up in my office.
Didn't know anything
until the police arrived.
It's birthdays and bowling leagues
until about 9 p.m.
then the drinkers take over.
It's a rougher crowd, but we haven't had
any serious problems until now.
Who was working last night?
Tish and Skye. They work the bar.
They're there now.
Uh, Wick Ammon. He's our bouncer.
He's over there.
And, uh, Andy the shoe guy.
- Anything else?
- Yeah, I have a question.
Uh, what's the best way to turn
a 10-7 split into a spare?
Um...
Line up on the 7 pin.
Aim for the far side,
hit it hard as you can.
Just try to get that pin action.
I got it.
- Anything else?
- No. Thanks for your help.
Mr. Ammon?
- Wick Ammon?
- Yes.
Agent Kimball Cho, FBI.
I understand you were working
security here last night.
You mind answering
a few questions?
Agent Kimball Cho of the FBI
know that I am a sovereign
citizen of the state of Texas
and do not recognize the legitimacy
of the federal government
or any police authority
you may claim to possess.
Nonetheless, I will answer
your questions voluntarily.
Great. Did you see Jeremy Geist
here last night?
I did. He arrived a little after 11.
Didn't see him leave, though.
Must've gone out through the side door.
- Did you talk to him?
- Said hello when he arrived.
Let me ask you something, agent.
Are you aware that the government
you've sworn allegiance to
is illegitimate
and illegally constituted?
Yes. Did you notice
anything about him?
Just that he kept to himself,
didn't talk much to people.
You also know
that federal income tax
is government-sanctioned theft
intended to prop up
a global conspiracy of bankers?
Tish. Did you notice Jeremy
arguing with anybody last night?
Nope.
Hardly spoke to anyone.
Pretty friendly most days,
but he didn't say five words.
So he wasn't drinking then.
- Club soda.
- Oh, well.
I would guess that's unusual
for a three-beer-a-night kinda guy.
Yeah. It is.
What about you, Skye? Did you notice
anything odd about Jeremy last night?
Not last night so much.
There was something strange
two nights ago.
What?
Jeremy was fine
when he got here.
A little while later,
he just shut down.
He sat at the bar,
he wouldn't talk to anybody.
Did he seem angry,
scared, sad?
Spooked. He looked really spooked.
Yeah, I go to the bar sometime.
When my shift is over.
Just to hang.
- Just to hang?
- Yeah.
Did you ever, uh? Did you ever
talk to Jeremy Geist
when you went over there, Andy?
Yeah. Sure.
Jeremy's a good guy.
- What'd you two talk about?
- I don't know.
- Sports, I guess. Um...
- Sports, you guess?
Bikes. You know, like that.
So, what does this have to do
with him getting murdered?
Are you nervous, Andy?
- No. Yeah.
- You sure?
- You seem kinda nervous. Okay.
- No. Not at all.
"Hey, Spackman!"
- Will you excuse me?
- Sure.
- This isn't working.
- Uh, I don't agree.
Our boy Andy over there,
he's wound up about something.
I think he's about to crack.
Uh, he's carrying drugs.
But if you want to bust someone
that has painkillers
without a prescription
he's definitely your man.
- You're calling that from here?
- Yes.
It is difficult to get anything
if we can't talk about
why Geist was here.
- Listen, I can't help you there.
- You're gonna have to.
I understand you wanna protect
your investigation
but this is a waste of time.
I thought you guys
were some innovative team
that was capable
of working outside the box
so what is
with your whining?
- Don't talk to her like that.
- We are not whining.
Yeah, it sounds like
you're whining.
You don't have
to talk to her like that...
- Hey. Back off.
- I won't back off.
You needn't talk to her
like that.
Look, we've spent
a lot of time and energy
trying to figure out who is
selling guns in this place.
And we're not gonna
let you guys come in
and mess up our investigation
until that person has been
identified and arrested.
- Do you got me?
- Fine.
Where is he going?
Can I have your attention please?
Thank you. There are these
things called microexpressions.
They are what shows on your face
when you feel something.
They're automatic.
You can't control them.
So when I tell you that Jeremy Geist
was an FBI agent
working undercover
everyone... Yes, there they are.
Showed a brief expression
of surprise.
- What the hell?
- His was bigger than most.
But when I tell you that Jeremy Geist
was investigating a gang
selling illegal firearms
out of this bar
only one person will show fear.
The person
who is afraid of being caught.
And that person is...
It's you, Tish.
- What?
- It's literally on your face.
There is your salesman.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wow. She was fast.
"Can I help you?"
I'm looking for
Supervisory Agent Abbott.
Yeah, oh, uh,
down that way, second door.
Thanks.
You asked for the salesman.
I found the salesman.
- Sales... The, the woman Saleswoman.
- Yeah.
Only we don't have her now.
See, she's in the wind.
She's probably across the border already.
Oh, now, she needs to get ready
before she leaves the country.
She'll need a little time.
We'll find her, Ken.
See? Every... Everything's fine.
No. No.
It is not fine.
First of all,
you haven't got any evidence.
And, you know, even if we do
manage to bring her in
what am I gonna do?
Pressure her with your say so?
I can't exactly get her to give up
the names
of the people
that she's working with, why?
Just because you say she did it?
All I can do now
is hold her for two days
while her lawyer sits there
and laughs at me
and while the rest
of her crew disperses.
So this is not okay.
This is a disaster.
He's not wrong.
Well, it's, it's possible
that I was a tad hasty.
But you got my ire up.
- Uh...
- Can I help you?
Michelle Vega. I was told to report
for assignment to your unit.
Vega. Right.
Agent Vega, Patrick Jane.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
- Pleased to be here, sir.
- Oh, you don't have to call me sir.
In fact,
please don't call me sir.
Save it for him.
Congratulations.
First assignment, huh?
I also see that you're, uh,
former military.
Uh, no.
Interesting that you would lie to me
so early in our acquaintance.
Uh, I, I wouldn't.
I mean, I'm not.
My dad was army.
Career, 37 years.
- Dennis?
- Vega.
Uh, could you go out
into the bullpen
and, uh, look for Cho or Lisbon.
They'll show you around
and I'll be out in a few minutes, okay?
Yes, sir.
So, gentlemen.
- What are we doing?
- Spackman.
I'm gonna make this up to you.
When this is over,
it's gonna be your birthday.
- Really.
- Candles on the cake and all, Ken.
And this is Agent Cho.
- Hi. Welcome.
- It's a pleasure.
- Teresa Lisbon.
- Hi.
And then there's Abbott.
And Jane, of course.
Jane. Is that the guy
in Abbott's office
with the, uh... shirt?
Is he an agent?
No, but he's part of the team.
He's, uh different.
Anything I should know
about him?
There's probably a few things.
Cho, Wylie,
you're working with Spackman
on tracking down Tish.
- You think she killed Geist?
- Probably not. if she did
she wouldn't have been
surprised he was FBI.
Which means we're still looking for
a viable suspect for the murder.
I'll call Austin P.D. to see if they can
track down the customers in the bar.
I'm running background checks
on everybody who works in the bowling alley.
Let's go.
Anything I can do, sir?
Ah, yeah. Relax, we'll talk,
and then I'll put you to work.
Yes, sir.
- Oh. Where you headed?
- Over to Geist's apartment.
- Poke my nose around.
- Yeah.
Both the bartender and the waitress
said that he was acting weird.
Any idea
what that was about?
- Not at all.
- Oh, great.
You know,
I don't know what's going on
- between you and Lisbon, but, uh...
- Nothing's going on.
Right. Right.
I understand.
That's the party line, right?
That's fine.
It's all good.
But on the off chance
that something is going on
I thought you might wanna know
that Marcus Pike is in the building
meeting with
a federal prosecutor.
Just an FYI.
"Okay, 324."
Geist. Geist. 322. Here.
Let me know
when you're out.
I will, thank you.
- Vega.
- Agent Vega. Patrick Jane.
How're you doing?
Settling in?
Yes, thank you.
Is there something
I can do for you, agent?
Yeah, you can stop calling me
agent for starters.
Now, your father was army
but you weren't?
- Yes, sir.
- I don't believe you.
You have military
in your posture, Vega.
- That is not genetic.
- Um...
Yes, I was at the Point.
West Point.
- But I didn't graduate.
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
It wasn't that big a thing.
No, not about the point.
Your, your father.
I, uh, I'm sure that was
a very difficult time for you.
How'd you know about that?
Well, you don't strike me
as the type of person
that would give up on things and...
What else would keep you
from finishing at the Point?
He had liver cancer.
It was very fast.
After that, um...
Just wasn't that interested
in the military anymore.
Of course not.
Is there something
I can do for you?
Uh, yes, there is.
Uh, when you were at Quantico
did they do
some sort of psychological
or, uh, emotional-profile
test thing?
- Yes, a pretty extensive one.
- Excellent.
I, I need Jeremy Geist's
psychological profile.
Do you think
you could get that for me?
Yes. Yes, of course.
I will get right on it.
Excellent work, Agent Vega.
As you were.
- Hey, Cho.
- "Yes?"
Austin P.D. just called.
A license-plate sweep
found a truck
registered to Tish Delaurio
in a parking garage
- in Travis Heights.
- Anybody sitting on it?
Two uniforms,
but it's all they can spare.
All right. I'll get a team
out there to pick her up.
Sir? I heard you say
you were gonna pick somebody up.
Would it be all right if I came along?
Just to observe.
You don't have
something else to do?
No. Agent... I mean,
Mr. Jane asked for something
- but it's on its way.
- Sure. You can come.
Thanks.
Wylie told me you worked
with Agent Lisbon in California
before you came here.
- Jane was there, too?
- Yeah.
Wylie told me
he was a psychic.
No, there's no such thing.
Jane's just good at reading people,
among other things.
How good?
As good as you can be.
Got rich doing it.
How does someone like that
end up working for the FBI?
It's a long story.
"We spotted her."
"She's coming up the ramp. Alone."
All right, let's move in.
You stay here.
Tish DeLaurio!
Get on the ground right now!
Don't move!
Stay where you are!
Turn around
and get down on the ground.
Don't shoot!
I'm not armed.
Stay back!
- Don't hurt me.
- Stay back.
- Please don't hurt me!
- Shut up.
Please. Please don't hurt me!
You okay?
Sorry. You told me to stay.
I did. Nice job.
Come on.
"You have lost your mind, Abbott."
Your people hounded my client
abused her when they took her
into custody.
Now you want her
to cooperate?
There was no abuse, Ellen.
- I got bruises.
- You ran, Tish.
When people do that,
we chase after them.
Of course she did.
She was falsely accused of a crime
she has nothing to do with.
Wait, wait.
You're not seriously suggesting
- that she ran because, what? She's innocent?
- Ken.
Now we believe
that your client is involved
with the sale
of illegal weapons.
It's a very serious crime.
What's your evidence?
The look on her face
when she was accused?
We've been checking into
Tish's bank account.
And there are
some substantial cash deposits.
- I'm a bartender. I get tips.
- Oh, yeah.
Some of which
were several thousand dollars.
That's your argument?
She's a bad bartender?
Look. We know
you didn't steal the guns
you just work for the people
that did.
Those are the people
that we want.
So if you give us their names
this won't be so bad.
Let her go right now
or I'm going in front of a judge
demanding her immediate release
and filing charges for harassment
and false arrest.
I guess we'll see you in court.
Let's go.
See this? This is exactly
what I was afraid of.
So you be sure to tell Jane
I say thanks a lot.
Think a judge will let her go?
In a heartbeat.
We got nothing.
We know where Jane is?
Uh, about a half-hour ago
he said he was going out
to read a report I got for him.
- And Lisbon?
- Uh, she just left.
Said she was going for a walk.
Imagine that.
Hey. I've been looking all over for you.
What are you doing out here?
Oh, I just needed some air.
What are you reading?
FBI's psychological report
on Jeremy Geist.
- Anything interesting?
- Couple things.
- Any things to do with the case?
- Maybe.
Jane.
You don't need to wait until I need
to know to tell me things, okay?
Not anymore.
You're right.
- Uh, it's okay...
- No. No. Please. Let me, uh...
- Let me apologize. I'm sorry.
- It's fine.
What's up?
Well, I went
to Jeremy Geist's apartment
and I noticed that he makes
his bed on the floor.
And sleeps with a little
nightlight next to him.
- Really?
- Mm.
- Some kind of trauma?
- Childhood trauma, I'd imagine
- so I, I checked it out.
- And?
And feast your eyes on that.
Whoa.
16 years ago, there was a kidnapping
in Geist's hometown, Pittsburgh.
A 12-year-old boy
named Justin Kellogg
was taken by two kidnappers.
They asked for $3 million
in ransom.
The family paid it,
but they killed the boy anyway.
They found his body
a couple weeks later.
And what does that
have to do with Geist?
Geist was a friend.
He was staying over
the night Kellogg was taken.
Shut up, kid! Or I'll have
your ass in a sling!
"He told the police
he didn't see anything"
"but he heard something."
One of the kidnappers
cursed at Kellogg.
Four months later,
a body turns up shot in the head
with some of the ransom
money on it.
That's one of the kidnappers.
His partner must have killed him.
They ever get anything
on him? The partner?
Never found or identified.
The waitress said Geist was
spooked about something.
You think Geist ran into the
missing kidnapper at the bar?
Who then killed him, yes.
- It's kind of a stretch.
- I know. I know.
But I looked into
Geist's phone records.
Yesterday, he called
the detective in Pittsburgh
who investigated
the Kellogg kidnapping.
Do you know what he said?
Left a message,
said he wanted to talk to him.
Okay. Yeah, I don't know. It's thin.
And we have
a more pressing problem.
- Oh, what's that?
- Tish DeLaurio is being released tomorrow.
And we have to figure out a way
to keep her in custody
otherwise, Spackman's case
is really dead
and we killed it.
Well, if she's selling guns
she must have
a supply somewhere.
We find that,
we can hold her.
Well, we'd better do it
in the next 18 hours.
How do we do that? She's not
gonna tell us anything.
Exactly, Agent Vega
which is how we're gonna crack
two cases for the price of one.
I don't understand.
You did a search for the gun
that killed Geist, right?
Yeah. Searched a ten-block radius.
Didn't find a thing.
- Perfect.
- Jane. Where have you been?
- Getting this.
- A hammer?
That's right.
That's a hammer.
And with this, we are gonna nail
Tish and Geist's killer.
Pardon the pun.
Oh, and someone's gonna have to stay up late.
- How late?
- Very late.
Morning, Tish.
What is this?
What are you doing?
We're gonna find those guns
you have hidden away.
Don't know
how you're gonna do that.
I'm not saying a word.
That's what I'm relying on.
Let's go.
Wylie, Vega,
you stay out here.
Cho will give you the signal.
You have the hammer?
Good. Radios?
All right.
Why is Jane
telling everyone what to do?
I thought Abbott was in charge.
He is.
Except when Jane is.
- And when is that?
- Uh, it, it kind of depends.
Uh, it's okay. Abbott trusts him.
And Jane knows what he's doing.
Usually.
Excuse me. Ladies and gentlemen.
We're with the FBI.
We're conducting a search
for some illegal
and highly dangerous weapons
we believe are on the premises.
And unless you work here,
I ask that you leave immediately.
Thank you.
Uh, sir, you can, uh, collect
your shoes later. Thank you.
- What weapons?
- Uh, the ones Tish here's been selling.
I need a witness.
I'm here against my will,
without an attorney.
It's a violation of my rights.
Smile, agents,
you're on camera.
What's going on?
We believe Tish
is involved with a group
that's selling illegal weapons
and that
they're being stored here.
- Here?
- Yes. And we're gonna find them.
Little thing called the fourth amendment.
You need a warrant.
- Don't you?
- Yes. And we can get one.
But we'd have to shut you down
and tear the place up.
But if you'll allow Mr. Jane
here to conduct a search
- we can be done in 10 minutes.
- Five, even.
Don't do it, Mason.
Don't think
it should be a problem.
All right. Thanks.
Uh, uncuff her, please.
We need her
to be able to move around.
Whatever it is
you're looking for
I don't know
anything about it.
Then you have nothing to lose.
Take my hands.
If you don't,
it's as good as confessing.
- Whatever.
- Thank you.
You think
you can keep a secret.
But the harder you try,
the more you show.
For example, Andy over there
doesn't want me to know
about that foil wrapped
package of cocaine
in his right-front pants pocket.
That's crazy.
Don't worry.
We're not narcs.
You don't want me to know
where the guns are
but you can't help react
when I get close.
- I'm not.
- No, not over here.
There's something going on
over here.
We're not just dancing.
Here, somewhere.
What the hell is that?
Military issue 45s. Looks like
there's about 20 of them.
Oh, wait a damn minute.
- Is that a rifle?
- Disassembled MK-4.
"Voilà."
Uh, no. You're a bunch of liars.
I don't know what's going on
but I got nothing to do with this.
Then how come you ran
when he called you out?
- Excuse me? If...
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Let go! Let go of me!
- No. I'm gonna take her outside.
You finish here with Jane.
- Let go!
- Okay, that was fun.
- "Seriously! Let go!"
- Should we do a two-for-one?
- What do you mean?
- We're gonna solve a second crime.
Two connected crimes, actually.
The kidnapping and murder
of a 12-year-old boy
and the shooting of an FBI agent.
The man that committed
those crimes is here.
And the gun he used is too.
I'm gonna find both of them.
- What was that?
- Nobody move. Just stay calm.
"Lisbon! Tish got Vega's gun!
Keep everyone inside!"
You heard him. Stay put.
This is the cool part.
Oh, my God.
She's trying to shoot at us.
- We gotta get some cover.
- Kitchen! Come on!
- Hey, come one.
- Get in the kitchen!
- Go in the kitchen! Get in, quick!
- Kitchen.
Go on, come on.
Mr. Hunston, put down the gun.
Do it now.
That's the gun that killed
Jeremy Geist, isn't it?
The gun
and the man who used it.
Did I call it
or did I call it?
You kidnapped Justin Kellogg.
And Jeremy Geist recognized you.
That's why you killed him.
You know what they say
about karma.
It's a bitch.
Geist was a nobody to me.
Just another barfly.
But the other night,
I said something to Tish.
I was pissed, I guess.
"Tish! Damn it!"
I am sick and tired
of picking up slack for you!
Now do it now, or I'll have
your ass in a sling!
"I could tell it was something
I said. The way I said it."
"He knew."
He came up later,
asked me where I was from
what I used to do.
Wasn't subtle.
So when he came in the other night
I kept an eye on him.
"Sure enough,
he broke into my office"
"looking for evidence, I guess."
Not that he was gonna find any.
But that was it.
I know you.
Three million
is a lot of money.
You killed
the other kidnapper
so you could keep the ransom
for yourself, didn't you?
Not saying I did,
not saying I didn't.
But he didn't get it,
did he?
Tish. I want to apologize to you
for earlier today.
We didn't tell you
what was going on.
Hope it wasn't
too uncomfortable.
Don't worry.
It's all going into the lawsuit.
Well, there's still
the matter of the guns.
Don't waste your time.
We know she won't talk.
Uh, Tish, uh, what I did with you
earlier today was a fraud.
We, in fact,
placed the guns in the bar.
It's a trick that works,
and I'm gonna prove it to you.
This is a map
of the neighborhood...
around the bar.
We know
you have the guns here.
So, what I'm gonna do is
I'm gonna move my hands around
and your reactions
are gonna show me where.
- What the hell is this?
- See, this is the deal.
If Tish agrees to cooperate
with Agent Spackman
and tell him where
the location of the guns are
and who she's been working with
she'll probably get a good deal.
Minimal time.
Definitely in here.
But if she refuses to cooperate
and Jane finds the guns
on this map here
well, all bets are off.
She gets the max.
25 to life.
Here.
Choice is yours.
In here.
This is absurd.
- Come on, Tish. Let's go.
- Almost there.
Tish!
What do you want?
Names?
Yes.
The people who have been stealing
the guns that you sell.
Every one of them.
And the location of the guns.
- Whatever you say...
- Sh.
All right.
You win.
Good call.
See?
It's your birthday.
Uh, excuse me.
Can I help you?
Jane.
Pike. Hello.
I was, uh,
looking for Teresa.
Yeah, I'm sure she's, um...
I'm sure
she's around here someplace.
Yeah, she probably is.
Beard looks good.
It's for an undercover thing.
So, it's, uh...
You and her.
Yeah. Um...
I'm sorry, we... we didn't intend
for it to happen like this.
I know it was the last thing on her mind
the idea of hurting you.
I know.
I know that.
So do you have a plan?
Uh, I don't really understand.
Well, I was offering her a life.
A home, a family if she wanted it
a future.
Have you thought
about any of that?
I haven't thought
that far ahead yet.
Well... Well, what are you offering her?
I mean,
other than Patrick Jane?
"Hey."
Excuse me.
What are you doing here?
Well, I was upstairs,
giving a deposition and...
I thought I would say hi.
- Stupid idea.
- No. It's fine.
Anyway.
It's good to see you, Teresa.
You too, Marcus.
Jane.
That was weird.
What'd he say?
Uh, he asked me
if I had a plan for you.
- Plan?
- Yeah, um...
I don't. I...
Well, I, I, I think
I, I know what feels right...
I, I think we know
what feels right
and I think that...
That that should be our guide.
"All right. Thanks."
- So do I.
- "Thanks."
- I do have one thing for you.
- What?
Turn around
and look out there.
It's a 1930 Cadillac V-16,
mint condition.
Rented it for the day.
Last chance. You sure
you don't wanna drive?
- I'm positive.
- Okay.
- You do know how to drive this?
- Oh, I'll figure it out.
Okay. I'm afraid to ask
how you got this.